[Music]
[Applause]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at se - radio dotnet SC radio
brings to relevant and detailed
discussions of software engineering
topics at least once a month
su radio was brought to you by I Triple
E software magazine online at computer
org slash software
welcome to software engineering radio my
guess is June rau he's a software
engineering researcher formerly of
LinkedIn who is embarking on starting a
company that is largely based on the
Apache Kafka project he's a researcher
and developer who has spent much of his
time researching MapReduce scalable
databases query processing and other
facets of the data warehouse and for the
past three years he's been a committer
to the Apache Kafka project which will
be a focus of our discussion so June rau
welcome to software engineering radio
thanks Jeff thanks for inviting me so to
get started let's talk about a couple
definitions so how would you define
streaming and how would you define
messaging yeah that's a good question
so streaming based on sort of my view of
it historically has been mostly
referring to systems or frameworks that
provides the capability of processing
one or more sequence of infinite events
so those framework typically provide
things like the ability of plugin
customized logic for processing those
events you can do things like filtering
with window based aggregation or string
based joins their framework typical also
provides things like parallelism it were
paralyzed the event for you you don't
have to worry too much about it and
those frameworks typically also covers
things like for tolerance so if one of
the processing unit is down you don't
have to worry about it because the
framework can restart the process in
some other missions for you so this is
my view of what this stream processing
system refers to so based on that
definition things like Apache
storm an apache spark and there's
another system that's has been built at
Lincoln called Apache Sansa falls into
the scattered category
these are a system that provides a
framework for processing so disciplines
of infinite events now one of the things
those systems have to worry about is
where do they get the data that's where
the messaging system comes in so one of
the key way for those stream processing
system to get data from is from a
messaging system or a Pops's system so
you collect you can look at Apache storm
the most popular way of way to get data
is from Apache Kafka which is a
messaging system and there's the
integration of whiskey and other
streaming systems like spark and Sam's
as well so that's sort of I you as the
difference or the relationship between
streaming and the messaging system so
another sort of the analogy if you want
to map that to the Hadoop or the Hadoop
art has two systems right one is the
MapReduce part which is really the
processing framework of those offline
data and then there's HDFS which is the
storage and delivery mechanism of those
data and these two system are coupled
together in the lowest way to provide is
offline computation framework and you
can view sort of this streaming
processing system as that you couldn't
have MapReduce
but more in the real-time world and the
messaging system like Kafka civil
equivalent or the counterpart of HDFS
but again it's for the real-time world
so that's interesting that you kind of
describe it as the Kafka and and storm
projects is sort of being an unbundling
of things that are frequently found
together or saw or in other domains
found together so and and I guess let's
talk a little bit more about
specifically what
Pachi Kafka is the the summary that I
found is a publish/subscribe messaging
system rethought as a distributed commit
log so what do you think of this
definition and why is it useful to draw
an analogy between messaging and a
distributed commit log yeah so yeah it
is true I think copter at a high level
the definition is really a sort of
messaging or pop stop system so the line
between messaging system and pop says
system is a libero blur these days
traditionally a messaging system has
been most referring to systems where you
sort of do this point-to-point message
delivery right so messages published
from one place and it's delivered to
another one and if you look at an and if
you look at the pop sub word there I
think the analogy is the difference is
messages can be consumed multiple times
I can surely buy mounted consumers so
but these days I think the lines blurred
because a lot of systems can support
both now why is the why do we draw the
analogy between a messaging system and a
commit log so there are I think there
are two things one is at the very high
level boasts messaging systems and a
commit log dealing with sort of a
sequence of append-only data so the
access tab pattern is pretty simple to
write a data into those systems you just
keep appending new data into your system
there's typically no updates you just
keep adding new things the way you
really is also pretty simple typically
just read those data sequentially now
because of such simplicity it comes a
lot of benefit basically we can
implement this system in a very
efficient way in terms of scalability
reliability and performance so that's
the
first sort of analogy the second thing
is so I came from the database
background so if you look inside a
database system right it knows the
database and has a commit log now that
commit log is actually the source of
truth of all data you store in a
database even though you're not it may
not be kept forever but that's actually
where the initial data comes in and from
that you can derive all other data use
you have in a database systems like data
you store in a table data store you
store in in the index so this is also
true for messaging system if you think
about all the consumers or the
downstream applications that gets data
from a messaging system messaging system
in some sense serves as the source of
truth for all those downstream systems
so that's sort of the second analogy
between a messaging system and a commit
log okay and so how does Kafka compared
to more traditional messaging systems
like ActiveMQ or RabbitMQ yeah that's
also a good question that's the question
that we got a lot I would summarize
there are two key differences one this
is a sort of a these are the differences
where caca has a little bit advantage so
one is Kafka is really designed for high
volume data if you look at traditional
messaging systems those system typically
are only responsible for storing data
that's generated in the database but if
you look at Kafka it's really designed
for it's really designed for systems
it's really designed for is really
designed for storing data such as
business metrics service logs
operational metrics and those data in
terms volume it's easily a hundred times
or a thousand times bigger than the data
you store in the database and
not something traditional messaging
system designed for and cafes redesign
photos for example copy design as a
distributive system from ground up so if
the volume of data increases you can
just easily add more machines into the
cluster to handle that volume of data
and there are quite a few optimizations
in various components where we do
batching and compression so that we can
handle this volume of data more
efficiently okay so that makes a lot of
sense so it's so kind of looking at the
size of the pipe from the ground up the
the you need that's right and saying we
need so we need something that's just
just way bigger than something like
ActiveMQ or RabbitMQ ah that's right so
you can think of it as a like a Big Data
version uh that of the messaging systems
so that's the first difference
the second element which is also
important is traditional messaging
systems are really designed for and only
for to the real-time use cases but for
takaka use cases we not only have the
more real-time use cases but an
important consumer or downstream
application of carpa is to feed data
into those offline pipeline so one of
the most important one of course is
Hadoop a lot of people are using Kaka to
get data into the Hadoop system so so
since in that case what we have is
system that you need handle both the
sort of real-time use case as well as
the non real-time or the batch or injury
use cases tradish a lot of traditional
messaging systems because they really
optimized for the real-time use case
they do things like buffering all the
messages or unconsumed messages in
memory so now imagine if you have a
downstream consumer like I do that's and
the maintenance for a couple of hours
right then you may not be able to buffer
all those data in your message broker
for that long so when we are go ahead
and because of that and for a lot of the
offline consumer use cases a lot of
traditional messaging systems the
performance for sway shot up confident
so would you describe Kafka as a a data
warehouse messaging system or is that
narrow of a definition I think yeah you
can you can sort of lies yeah I think it
is a sort of warehouse of data you can
think of as warehouse data but is really
a place where you can collect all types
of data and you can feed that into
different platforms one important tab
trad for a pipe is to feed that into the
sort of warehouse or the offline system
but you can equally use the same system
to feed data into a more real-time
platform so it's a sort of the
integration point for both the offline
and more real-time consumption ok that's
great so now that we have sort of a
framework of an idea for our listeners
for what Kafka is let's talk a bit about
the basic vocabulary of Kafka and kind
of drill down into how it works so maybe
you could talk about how some of the
central components work so could you
maybe talk a bit about topics and
producers and consumers and brokers yeah
so at the very high level Kafka has is
very similar to traditional messaging
systems it has this three-tier concepts
in the middle we have this broker layer
this is actually where messages are
stored and served and of course we have
the producer tier these they actually
are the publishers of the messages and
we have the consumers these are the
system that make subscription one or
more of those feed of data and the data
just get delivered to those consumers so
these are at a very high level sort of
three layers of and it
around a Kaka now politics are
essentially the unit of the logical unit
of defining individual feeds you can
think of each topic corresponds to like
a virtual queue and when you publish
messages of course you publish message
to a topic so then your data is added
into one of those virtual queues and
when you consume a message consume data
you typically subscribe to one or more
of those topics so then all those data
stored in those corresponding virtual
queue or virtual Channel will get fed
into your system there is also this
low-level concept called petitions which
is associated with topic now each topic
physically can have one or more
petitions and the reason we have this
petition is really for parallelism so
the more you can sync of like a virtual
Channel physically dividing into
multiple physical cues or channels and
those individuals suck use or sub
channels can be stored independently on
different missions and that's a way of
getting more parallelism out of our
system and when you say parallelism do
you also mean like redundancy or fault
tolerance or is it or is it mostly just
to speed things up I think it has it
mostly has to do with speeding things up
so logically different partitions can be
sort of consumed independently and
whether you replicate those data or not
and so the more partitions you have in
terms of both the producer and client is
sort of the more parallel channels you
can have so that it's a way of
increasing the degree of parallelism now
each of a partition can be further
replicated and that is a way that that
can use to provide a reliability of the
system but it's not related to what we
have in terms of parallelism so
messaging typically has two models at
least you know there's there are two you
could discuss queuing and pub/sub
publish/subscribe and with queuing you
have a pool of consumers that read from
a server and each message goes to only
one consumer so in queueing maybe you
have like a list of tasks that the
server needs accomplish just once and it
just has consumers that are you know
people receiving each of those tasks and
then in pub/sub the message is broadcast
to all consumers so Kafka has a single
consumer abstraction called a consumer
group that generalizes both of these
could you talk a bit about consumer
groups and and how and why they were
conceived yeah suddenly I think consumer
group yeah it's pretty interesting so as
you said it actually covers sort of
boasts use patterns in one case what he
can have is you can have just a single
consumer group and in that group you can
have multiple consumers and what they do
is they sort of jointly consume one
normal other topics so for example so
you have like a two consumers in the
same consumer group then a topics data
will be hopefully evenly divided
half-and-half between these two
consumers so that's sort of a way of
increase the degree of parallelism in
the consumer in a lot of use cases where
the logic in the consumer can be a
little bit CPU intensive or time
consuming of course if you have more
degree of parallelism then you can use
more CPU power and other resources to
speed up the processing of the data so
that's one use case another use case of
course is you can have multiple consumer
groups on the same topic and these are
the multi subscription model and in that
case each consumer group will get a
complete feed of order in a topic so
this is actually intended
for there's just lots of applications
they want to consume the same data but
they just want to process them in a
slightly different way or for different
applications and this multi subscription
model is a very powerful way for those
applications to sort of consume notice
data independent of each other
and you can actually have thought even
for multiple consumer groups within each
consumer group you can still have those
multiple consumers so super can combine
the benefit of the multi subscription
and the degree of parallelism who is in
each instance of the consumption so
that's how we sort of combine both
concept into this consumer group and
what other facets about the relationship
between producers and consumers are
unique to kafka yeah in terms of yeah I
think it actually won a good question I
think one of the things if we can help
if you can pair Caprica with traditional
messenger systems one of the things we
don't have is some of the more
traditional messaging api's such as like
the GMS GMS has like a rich set of
features in terms of like order delivery
priority is kind of stuff dad we don't
have in khakha as I said earlier copy is
really designed for high volume of data
and for feeding data in the efficient
way so that we don't have other features
that's existing in traditional messaging
systems and so this is does this lead to
some trade-offs where there are sort of
like explicit use cases where Kafka just
doesn't really make sense as your
messaging system of choice right so it
depends on your application
on one hand rocket does support some
basic features that a lot of
applications want to have such as the
guarantee of delivery you know there's a
like producer side API allows you
configure when you can get an
acknowledgement when you publish a
message different ways of acknowledging
gives you different guarantees on
durability that actually a lot of
application of the users are using for
the applications now what we don't have
is some other things like the order of
the priorities order to deliver like a
various Ottoman order delivery so if you
have requirements of that then either
you have to implement in your
application or yeah I just have to use
some other messaging systems that gives
you this capabilities so talking more
broadly or historically there have been
a lot of platforms over the the last few
years you know we've mentioned some of
them so far so what do you think are the
factors that are driving the emergence
of this important technology and and and
sort of like like where you know you're
kind of at the forefront of developing
this kind of stuff so what do you see
changing in the future and how do you
see like what evolution of this domain
do you see yeah that's also an
interesting question so I see there are
two important factors that have changed
one is sort of the volume or the type of
data that people are collecting
historically Melissa the data people
that are interest just database data but
in the last 10 or 15 years people start
collecting so other those what we call
big data so what are those data these
are data such as business metrics these
I like the pageviews impressions clicks
search keywords people typed in this
also include operational matrix or the
GN max Iowa stats CPU stats this also
includes all the service laws and like
Jim like log4j logs this logs on maybe
some other service calls
now in terms of volume of data this data
is easily two to three orders magnitude
bigger than the data stored in
traditional database systems in terms of
value you know these data provide a lot
of insights that's actually valuable for
lots of downstream applications
so that's trend number one the second
thing which is also related is which is
the questioning why people are only
starting to collect this data so the
more recently in sort of like fifteen or
twenty years ago this extra has to do
with another trend which is the
emergence of a lot of scalable
specialized vertical systems if you like
a group Hadoop is a it's a specialized
scalable system for doing offline
processing traditional a lot of those
things you know multiplies you can do
this kind of stuff is in Oracle or
terror data which is expensive but what
we do did is very special they basically
take just take one aspect of it which is
offline processing on the system and
made it more scalable on commodity
hardware as a result they can provide an
offline processing solution in a more
economical way and because of that
people actually can now afford to store
this large volume of data if they want
to do offline processing
in Hadoop they don't have to acquire
those expensive Oracle Altera beta
innocence is so this kind of trend is
not only happening in the offline world
but it's actually starting to happening
in many other vertical specialized the
names so if you're like how to search
there is a you'll access search that's
doing the sort of scalable version on
commodity hardware in the search domain
and if you looked at key value stores
right there are lots of system that are
provides capability of storing and
retrieving like point data in in a
scalable and economical way on commodity
hardware
and if you look at there are lots of
like a growth engines that was a like
system that can do graph processing but
again sort of commodity Hardware in the
machina economical way there are lots of
like a streaming system that also these
are designed to be designed on commodity
hardware that you can scale in a more
economical way and do you think that the
the the big cost of storing this kind of
data is is sort of trending towards the
fact that you have to maintain it as
opposed to you know whether or not you
can afford to store it yeah I think both
aspects are important the first of
course is upfront cost right how much
does it cost for you to acquire the
software and corresponding hardware that
of course if you if your software is
like free like open source and your
hardware is can run or depend only
dependent on commodity hardware then
it's going to be a lot cheaper than you
have to pay a premium proprietor
software and you have to pay a high
premium expensive storage boxes that
were just commodity boxes with large
local SATA drives that's the first
aspect bit the second thing of course
once you have your system in place you
have to operate that right so they are
of course the the more is the more
instances or a larger the class you have
the potentially the more overhead of
monitoring on of operationalizing yet so
there i think that a lot tooling would
definitely help if you have lot of a
tooling and monitoring in place then it
doesn't really matter whether you are
monitoring in class of 10 nodes or
clocks of like a hundred nodes because
and other things can just be integrated
together with the right alert and
monitoring set in place so that will
certainly help to drive down the opera
or cost all those systems okay so let's
let's get back to talking a little more
about Kafka specifically so maybe you
could describe a in you know I know
you've touched on some some more
abstract examples of of Kafka maybe you
could talk about a more specific use
case winds where somebody would want to
deploy Kafka and sort of describe how
they would go about you know deploying
it and connecting the different
components right so at a high level this
system goes back to the changes of of
industry trend I mentioned ittle bit
earlier so because of those existence
out emergence of those very specialized
so scalable systems so not only if you
look at those they need to they need to
be fed with the same type of data for
example if you have a collection of log
data right of course you want to feed
that data into Hadoop for offline
processing but equally important you
probably won't feed data ain't data into
your search system so that we can search
any of the longer currents quickly
that's a lot of the business what's plan
does right and equally if you have for
example stream or like operational data
of course you want to feed that into
your offline system but your problem to
feed that into some of your real-time
monitoring system so they can monitor
and graph those data so sort of
questions where do all those independent
system get their data from you sort of
need like an integration point that
where all those systems can get its data
from now a lot of those systems actually
unlike Hadoop they action more real time
so you can't really just integrate that
in your warehouse offline system because
in terms latency these system may not be
good enough to provide data feed to some
of the more real-time applications or
frameworks such as
real-time search and graphing so cough
is sort of a fuse in that role because
it's a system actually designed for
collecting and storing high volume of
data it actually can provide speed to
any number of downstream applications
and those those applications can be sort
of more real-time can deliver those
system can also be offline so you can
sort of it as a like integration hub for
all this big data now in terms of
adoption what we have seen of course is
people are picking up sort of various
pieces one common use case of cause is
people are using Kafka as this ingestion
pipeline to get data into Hadoop but at
the same time they also have application
one normal of the application for
real-time use case you know be it a
specialized real-time application or
some of the streaming processing frame
of a adopting or some of the real-time
search system they are adopting so so
because of those need of more than one
application of the same data so copper
surgery is very important for them to
get those various pipelines working so
that's one of the common pattern we see
copper gets adopted has there been any
have there been any implementations
you've you've seen that have like really
surprised you and maybe ended up maybe
even changing the direction of of the
project or you know sort of introduced a
reason for adding some new features you
wouldn't have predicted we are think so
far I think there are lots of features
that we know are required as complicates
or more and more adopted things like
security which is important and in that
donator we don't see too many like
surprises in terms like a future feature
requirements we also surprised
occasionally just the way people are
using system you know there are
there are lots of things that we sort of
a didn't plan to have people using that
way but you know people use it using it
anyway some of them sometimes is it's
not really my dear use case and
sometimes you just we surprised that
Kafka actually works when people use it
that way
for example one of the things we were
surprised at you know there are lots of
there are at least one use case that are
using cough cats or as a message
delivering mechanism and the way to send
messages you know each message is is
sort of gigantic those are like could
each message can be a gigabyte of course
you can configure a Kafka to do things
like that but it's certainly not
something that we really design it for
and but we're just surprised that you
know people are using it and then sort
of worked in this limited context there
are other use cases like people are sort
of trying to use car more like a key
battle store yeah where they just sort
of randomly consume messages from
different places that also sort of a
subtle can work but it's not really
something that company is really
designed for so that I would say
architecture was you have a use case
like that probably a key value store is
more appropriate for those use cases
yeah that's really surprising that
sounds like the type of thing where it's
you know you have somebody with a hammer
and everything looks like a nail
that's right so in in the 2011 paper
about Kafka there is a distinction that
is made between application data and log
data and so this distinction has become
less clear over time do you think Kafka
is still viewed as a log record
messaging tool or and you know is it is
it less acceptable now compared to three
years ago if some of the log records are
dropped yeah so one of the things we
have seen will cause you know the way
cough could get adopted typically starts
from people putting in log data
um and that's actually what Copley is
really designed for and it's a powerful
way to store and serve this kind of
large volume of data and arguably maybe
for long data you can argue maybe it's
okay to lose a few messages from time to
time but over time of course what people
want to have is once you have a pipeline
that can soar high volume of data right
then people would think oh why can't we
move all the data including some of the
more application or maybe database data
into this pipeline so then for those
data of cause those are more important
data than log data some of the
durability and reliability guarantees or
be stronger so that's one aspect of it
another thing is when you publish data
to Kafka one of the things you can do is
sort of do this semantic partitioning
instead of just random distribution so
for some applications maybe what you
want to have is for example all the
messages associated it with like a
particular like user ID right you want
that to be consumed by one consumer so
the most convenient way you can do that
is to partition the messages by this
partitioning key which can be the use ID
and you guarantee order messages
belonging to the same user ID will show
up in one partition and as a result will
be consumed by only one consumer now to
do things like that it actually requires
each of the partition to be made highly
reliable and available right because now
if you imagine if one of the partition
is offline and now you have a message
semantically based on the key it has to
go to that petition if that partition is
not available
what would you do you know you probably
have to drop it or if you match to a
different partition then essentially
that changed the meaning of your
semantics which may not be ideal either
so that's why for those cases
reliability and durability is actually
equally important you know when you have
even just log data so for that in the
last couple of years we actually have
spend a second amount of time on Kaka
just to add the reliability and
durability supporting Kafka so what we
did is for each partition of conker you
can have multiple replicas and when you
publish a message a message will be a
redundantly stored multiple replicas
typically in different brokers then if
any of the broker failures there's a
logic in cognate that allows the system
to continuously as function in when
there are individual broker failures so
from the end users perspective was to
produce and consumer it's as if nothing
has happened because the underlying
systems were route the connection from
the client to the alive brokers that has
the same copy of the data is that one of
the things important things we added in
Kafka is this performed by zookeeper yes
I think the way this works is we use
zookeeper for storing some important
state information petition in terms the
amount of data is not a lot there's only
like maybe a few bytes of information
that we need to store the topic
partition and what we saw there critical
information as who is the leader of a
petition I think in the world of web
replication typically you will have
multiple replicas associated with a
petition one of them is testing testing
it as the leader which takes order
rights and the other replicas are
followers which just takes data from the
leader so when the leader fails
cause you need to be able to quickly
elect a new leader and and then continue
serving data from the new leader so we
rely on zookeeper to store information
like who is the current leader of a
petition and who and equally important
who who are the correct or possible
candidates for becoming a new leader had
the original leader fails right in it
what's interesting is it seems like the
ability to just I guess offload oh I'm
not sure how much energy is offloaded
onto zookeeper but you know it sounds
like a significant amount and it makes
me think back to the what you said
earlier on in the conversation about how
you know the Kafka is analogous to you
know if you look at Kafka and storm it
it's analogous to unbundled components
of Hadoop and it makes me think it's
interesting that you know you you you
have zookeeper that's essentially just
like a Lego block then you just are
isn't is you know now a central
component of Kafka and so all that makes
me think about what are like can you
conceive of future type of components
maybe open source or not that would be
built on top of Kafka yeah so that is is
a good point I think for now Kafka you
can think of it as though like a place
where a feed of data is provided and you
know given the sort of reliability and
durability guarantees we have it it is
possible for people to store like the
source of truth data in Kafka now in
some sense you can view it as sort of
the commit log in the database world now
from the source of truth of data there
are lots of system that you can
potentially you're on top a bit too to
get a feed of data and then sort of a
convert data into a format that's easier
for processing for a particular vertical
domain so there has been systems for
example in the key value store denying
where it relies upon so that there
should be it can be the log as the
centerpiece for storing and recovering
data now we haven't tried this in cata
but it is possible for someone to take
comprehend and use it as it was sort of
a commit log as a source of truth and we
were other surrounding systems like
maybe another key value store or other
storage systems around it okay
interesting so to to go back to a little
bit more about the the pub/sub model
because I I see that as a fairly
important to this discussion and I you
know I'd like to just maybe even if this
involves you know rehashing some stuff
that has already been discussed I think
it it be worthwhile so coming back to
the the topic of of pub/sub so each
topic is analogous to a published
channel in the pub/sub model and you
know as i understand each of these
topics has one or more partitions which
is a block of memory that is allocated
to it where new messages are appended
and at any given time you have each
subscriber to a topic that has consumed
up to some point on that partition would
you describe that is it do you think
that's an accurate description of how
partitions and and and channels work
yeah that's actually it's not 100%
accurate okay so one of the things what
we do in Kafka is
remember earlier I think copy is really
designed to optimize for oppose the sort
of a real-time consumption as well as
the offline consumption so one of the
things that requires a think about is in
terms of buffering messages so if you
buffer like or unconsumed messages in
memory of course that just limits how
how offline applications you can support
right because memory is limited
you can't essentially pop for everything
if a consumer is gone for a long time so
what we do in the broker is we we don't
actually allocate a lot of heap space
for storing messages so every time we
get a message or certain messages from
the producer we simply just append it to
the corresponding fire channel on the
local disk of course we don't flush data
immediately for better performance we
sort of flush data in those fire channel
to disk only periodically but we don't
really keep a copy in the JVM he keeps
pace we actually immediately just put a
data into the fire system but most of
the time fire system has his own page
cache so chances are those data are
still in in memory but you can see in
the page cache managed by our system for
us it's just that we don't have to
manage that in the JVM heap space which
is a lot better for GC tuning and other
things now in terms of consumer we do
the same thing we do similar things we
use the sort of UNIX stand fire API to
send data from a local fire channel to a
remote socket directly again in from the
consumers perspective we don't have to
take any heap space by first copying the
data from the fire channel into an
application space then copying the data
from the application space into the Remo
socket we sort of a rely on the
operating system to do us to do this for
us more efficiently so because of that
Kafka at least a broker is actually very
efficient in terms of JVM heap memory
usage typically we don't require a lot
of he space and we only need something
that limited the kind of tuning for GC
GC management because we don't have a
lot of a permanent space that's taken by
the JVM heap a lot of the memory
consumption are like transient a request
okay that makes sense so then let's talk
about another aspect of against
distributed systems in general and how
it pertains to Kafka specifically so I'd
like to talk about durability so our our
messages recoverable across restarts and
failures right so yes they are different
like failures on the broker side as I
mentioned earlier we added this
replication support so within the single
cluster messages can be a redundant list
or multiple brokers so now if Y in real
quick is would you say a broker is is
synonymous with a topic partition a
broker is actually thinking like yeah
just like a server or node where
multiple partitions data can be stored
upon okay okay so it's sort of like a
engine where we store those messages and
in the cluster you can have multiple
those storage engines but the popeck
partitions or replicas they are sort of
spread around into those storage engines
and each storage engine or broker can
store typically stores multiple
petitions
got partitions from different topics
that's right of course each partition
typically corresponding to a local fire
directory and sort of Texas uh has its
own set of fires from other topics so
there's going to be isolation at a disc
level now in terms of reliability if you
configure a topic to have multiple
replicas and we can the program on a
broker side it can tolerate broker
failures the common failure in the copy
class of cause is total speak or you
know soft failure the broker is actually
healthy you just want to deploy new code
on making new config changes because of
that you have to bring one or maybe each
of the broker in the class it down and
then restarted so that's actually maybe
80% or maybe 90% of the failure cases in
a calculus class sir
so with replication of course we can't
handle this kind of failure very
effectively we have the logic to
automatically just fire over the leader
of each other partition to another
replica and all the clients will just
behave seeing it seamlessly in these
cases so it sounds like it's not really
within the spec of Kafka to backup
messages to a durable store is that
accurate yeah actually that's sort of
ignore yes this yeah the replication
really deals with phone message you know
where we store those and how we keep
make sure we keep them in sync
among those different replicas then a
second issue which is of sort of what
you are pointing out is how long do we
keep a message around in the Kafka
cluster so that which this is also to be
unique with cava is the retention of a
message is
actually not driven by consumption as in
typical messaging systems in the sense
that a message is not like the leader
from the koepcke ones or consumers have
finished consuming of this message
rather messages retain based on
retention policy and that policy can be
driven by time you can for example keep
the messages for like seven days or
maybe a month whatever you feel that you
need those for and the course can also
be retained based on sizes see maybe you
want to keep like say a terabytes of
data right around so the one of the
important aspect with this kind of
retention is it's actually a pretty
useful feature and what it gives you is
what we call the rewind ability from the
consumers in the sense that a consumer
after finished consuming a message if it
wants to
it actually can consume the message
again as long as that message is still
within the retention window the there
there's some use cases of this I think
one important use case is this can deal
with like application error or logic
error very effectively so imagine like
you have a application that consumes a
feed of data from Kafka and do things
like standardization right you
standardize each of the data and into
some canonical format but let's say at
some point you push some new software
and you have like a serious bug and you
realize that only the later maybe and
now into it you say oh or the data that
process in the last hour isn't is not
usable because because of the back so
now what you do so with this sort of
retention policy what you can do is you
can actually rewind the consumption of
your messages
from like an owl or maybe two hours ago
the point where the Bakke code is
introduced as long as those messages are
still retained there you can actually
just reapply the new logic which assumed
you know presumably have fixed that bug
and just runs through those same data
again then you can recover or the you
can correct all the mistakes you have
made on the previous computation logic
it sounds like a super important feature
that's right
so that's something that not all the
traditional messengers provide and
right.we allows you to go back in time
that's right the ability to reconsider
messages over time and fixing Occupation
logic is one of the important use cases
what is cool so one of the words that we
we hear a lot on on this podcast is the
word micro service so what is what is
the word microservice mean to you and is
that is that something that's
appropriate to this conversation as you
know is what Kafka is and and what it
provides yeah so actually I'm not 100%
sure what those micro-service means what
what what do you what's your
interpretation of those microservice
sure sure so what I would think of a
microservices is something that is a
service that it that can be uh to put it
in this context a service that could
have a call made to it over a message
broker just a small service that you
know you know if X needs to get done you
could make a call to it over whatever
message broker you have the service gets
performed and you know the advantage to
these sorts of services that you know as
you module as you can modularize them
and it becomes easier to scale more
instances of them yeah but me I you know
as I understand about the
word microservices that it it means
different things to different people so
that's part of why I brought it up but
if but if you're not even really you
know familiar with it or comfortable
discussing with it that's totally fine
yeah I'm 100 but I think sounds like is
that sort of more an ad hoc use of the
message broker where you know you want
to like a start up some like services
just for like a short window of time and
you want to do some processing of the
message and then and after that you can
just stop the service yeah that's that's
exactly what I'm saying and I'm just
kind of wondering if if Kafka serves
that purpose ever yeah actually yeah one
of the things actually this actually has
to do with the multi subscription model
that Kafka provides because one of the
powerful things that we see people is
enabled with khakha is the ability to to
do debugging on Kafka so this can happen
in the production environment but more
than it happens in the sort of casting
or the pre-production environment where
of course you have all the applications
that's written up to consume like a feed
of data but sometimes is actually if if
the application doesn't work as expected
right you know how do you know what went
wrong so the ability of doing multi
subscription allows you just to easily
tap into like a topic user from a
command line tool or on a console where
you can actually see what the data are
and and then based on that potentially
we have a bad idea where the is a
problem is the you don't get the right
data or there's something hours in the
application okay so that's sort of like
a special case that maybe micro-service
that you are referring to sure sounds
good so in terms of the vector but a
little bit more about the the
development of Kafka
why was the
Scala the language of choice like did
you and more specifically did you
consider Erlang right I think yeah when
we started is I think Jake Raz was the
first developer of Kafka around that
point you know he was Scala is getting
it'll be popular and he's thinking of
like a learning Scala so that's why I
know he picked at Scala it's sort of a
way of just to try it out and then see
how it works and from developers
perspective it's always like interesting
and exciting to try some new like
promising programming languages now for
Scala I think what we benefited a lot
from Scala is is mainly the sort of
conciseness of the syntax we use a lot
of the functional support and the
collections which allows writing code of
iterating collections very convenient
and because of that if you look at the
Kafka code base
it's actually signal is poor compared
with some of the similar system but
written in Java and we benefit a lot of
just from the Scala concise syntax but
one of the things we found a little bit
difficult with Scala this is action
mostly has to do with the Kline's which
is because Scala is sort of emerging
technology is not as mature as like Java
in terms of like preserving binary
compatibility just because it's early in
some of early releases Scala really have
to break the binary compatibility so
some of the byte code generated in early
version of Scala won't be able to run on
a new version of Scala
right so this actually creates some
problem for upgrading our clients
because a lot of our clients maybe they
are of course using Kaka because of that
and I have a scholar dependency but they
may use some other components which
could also be Scala dependent
maybe we're dragging a different version
of Scala
now if the Scala version is not
compatible then it makes the upgrading
of those clients very painful so that's
sort of one of the things that we find
is a bit hard with Scala so we're trying
to address this issue by sort of a
rewriting the client components just in
pure Java so hopefully this we're still
allow us to get most of benefit from
using the concise syntax in Scala but at
the same time makes the client upgrade a
little bit easier going forward that's
great so this has been a great
discussion of Kafka where can listeners
go to learn more about Kafka or maybe
even your your work on the project yeah
I think the best place to do that I'll
cause is just go to our website see if
you search Kafka you know what in using
Google I think akka probably is Apache
kapha is probably the first or the
second link so there it has some
documentation that describes what copper
is and how copy is designed for and some
of the examples of how to use our API s
and you can download a code and there's
a QuickStart that you can follow just
try it out and from that web page we
also have like link to our JIRA system
in Apache if you are interested in
contributing there you can just search
for some of the newbie labels in the
giro system that product will give you
some like a low-hanging fruit that you
can give it a try
and we also have like a wiki that
describes some of the future release
plans and future features so does that
make a more
substantial development work that's
required so if you are like a more
experienced contributor to conquer some
of the future approaches may be of
interest to you right now some of the
new things that are coming out of
capital and one is we are in the process
of rewriting some of those consumer
api's as I mentioned to to reduce to
remove the Scala dependency and to just
make the API more feature complete and
better performing another thing that's
coming that that's coming up soon is the
security support in Kafka is in crews
you know probably authentication and
maybe sending summer data in the
encrypted way we also have thoughts on
how to sort of protect Kafka in a
multi-tenant environment
so hopefully different users don't
affect each other especially if one of
the application had a bug and becomes
like a runaway user so we have some
thoughts on how to use a coder system to
to prevent things like that from
happening
so all those information can be found
our main our apache website and we also
have like Apache mailing lists for both
the user and developer and if you're
interested in just subscribe to those
mailing lists and get a feel of what's
happening in the capital world that's
great all right well June rau thank you
so much for coming on software
engineering radio it's been a pleasure
yeah thanks a lot yeah okay all right
you have a great day you too
all right thank you
[Music]
thanks for listening to s-see radio an
educational program brought to you by I
Triple E software magazine for more
information about the podcast including
other episodes visit our website at SE -
radio net to support us you can
advertise su radio by clicking the de
crédit delicious or slash buttons on the
site or by talking about us on Facebook
Twitter or your own blog if you have
feedback specific to an episode please
use the commenting feature on the site
so that other listeners can respond to
your comments as well this and all of
the episodes of se radio is licensed
under the creative commons
two-point-five license please see the
website for details thanks again for
your support
[Music]
[Applause]